PAUL HENRY BENJAMIN ALONTE III

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

PROFILE

I have about 12+ years of experience specializing in creating responsive and intuitive Web Applications using modern client-side technologies such as ReactJS, Angular, TypeScript, MaterialUI, JavaScript and Custom web components. I actively collaborate with Product leaders and stakeholders to gather requirements and develop UI/UX designs leveraging best practices in Research, Visual Design, Information Architecture, and Prototyping.

Currently, I'm enhancing my development workflow by integrating Al tools, enabling faster application development, increased efficiency, and higher-quality outcomes.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

ReactJS, Angular Javascript,
Typescript, MaterialUI, CSS (SCSS),
HTML, RXJS, Redux, RTKQuery, APIs,
e2e Cypress Bootstrap, Accessibility,
UI/UX Design, Wireframe, Information
Architecture, Prototype,
Some backend: NodeJS, Express,
MongoDB, Ruby on Rails

CONTACT INFORMATION

Mobile: +49 15231410054 Email: paulalonte@gmail.com Website: http://paulalonte.github.io/

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulalonte/

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

Labforward Berlin, Germany (February 2022 - Present)

- Responsible for the improvements to the frontend architecture of an IoT Software Service platform, focusing on scalability, modularity, and long-term maintainability.
- Implementing good User Experience improving accessibility (WCAG compliance), performance (lazy loading, code splitting, optimized rendering), and responsiveness across devices
- Writing end to end testing (Cypress)
- Actively improving code maintainability by refactoring legacy components. including versions of React, Typescript, and supporting libraries.

APPLICATION ENGINEER FRONTEND

e-bot7 Munich, Germany (July 2021 - December 2021)

- Responsible for Developing user-facing features
- Responsible for Improving existing user flows; build reusable components; optimize client application performance
- Implementing new functionality around managing our bot platform
- Responsible for ensuring the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Deltek Makati, Philippines (November 2019 - June 2021)

- Responsible for driving the development of our project and resource planning solution People Planner.
- Responsible for developing frontend application in Angular/Typescript connecting to the backend written in C#/.Net.
- Responsible for development and quality assurance in the Philippines and Denmark
- Undertake analysis, design, coding and testing activities

CERTIFICATES

- Web Development Bootcamp 2023
- Suitecommerce Developer
- Google Rich Media Developer

FEATURED PROJECTS

Samsung, Intel, Warner Bros, L'oreal, Wyeth, Samsonite, Axe, Mentos, Garnier, Del Monte, Lipton, Dove, Medicol, Ayala Land, Globe, Ponds and Marlboro

EDUCATION

OLGC Polymedic

2003 - 2005

Bachelor of Science in Health and Science Education (2 year/associate degree)

Informatics Computer Institute

2001 - 2003

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

LANGUAGE

English, Filipino

UI/UX DEVELOPER

Willis Towers Watson BGC, Philippines (June 2017 - November 2019)

- Responsible for all UI code in application development including Implementation of preprocessor (SCSS) in our project for easy maintenance and flexibility in our code
- Responsible for implementing UI standards in our project to ensure its consistency and reviewing of UI codes before deployment (includes UI Architecture)
- Responsible for implementing Web Accessibility for people with disabilities (Screen Reader and Keyboard)

TECHNICAL CONSULTANT

Oracle + Netsuite Makati, Philippines (July 2015 - May 2017)

- Lead for style guides and UI code development to ensure the standardization of design and layout in web development
- Responsible for end to end delivery/development of Ecommerce and ERP projects from start up to go live
- Directly collaborates with onshore clients to discuss specific requirements including ui design and functionality

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

Cognizant Makati, Philippines (September 2013 - June 2015)

- Assigned to Google Account and Certified to develop Google Rich Media Web Applications
- Developing Youtube Mastheads, Mobile in-app, Interactive in-stream, and Google Display Network Lightbox units.
- Development using Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, Canvas Animation, CSS Animation, Flash, Actionscript 3

FRONTEND/FLASH DEVELOPER

Movent BGC, Philippines (February 2010 - August 2013)

- Responsible for creating web interactive applications for Desktop, Mobile and Tablet. Including Facebook games
- Creating Augmented Reality Applications for mobile
- Responsible for design and concept for Interactive Projects Exposed to ground up projects up to go live.